SUE DARBY

Sue@sue-a-darby.com www.sue-a-darby.com

SUMMARY

I am a specialist at bridging the gap between business managers and IT professionals, among the rare group of people who can translate business needs to the IT staff and the mid to high levels of technical information to the business users. I excel at identifying execution steps, building processes and diagrams with detailed instructions for use.

I am passionate about helping people do tasks more efficiently and am always looking for a better way to solve problems.

Get to know me via www.sue-a-darby.com and my network of websites I have been working on for 15+ years. I have a variety of topics and samples spread across 8 sites.

EXPERIENCE

IA3 10 / 2015 - Present

Technical Writer & Webmistress

iA3 is a service that gives you access to information and analytics about any automated systems you may have; anywhere, anytime. I am currently involved with the website, social media, Wikipedia and marketing efforts while learning and growing into a role as a technical writer.

STATE OF ALASKA 02 / 2014 - Present

Senior Services Technician

*Effectively explain ideas and information to both technical and non-technical users *Convert New Provider Certification Application to fill in PDF for public use *Design and implementation of the and Habilitation Homes Project to connect licensed homes with recipients and certified agencies; original and Critical Incident Report *Tracking system and statistics generation *Design improved filing and labeling system, archive process, electronic file system, document naming structure, letter template editing and standardization *Design charts and graphs for Unit, Department, State and Federal reports; UML diagrams, translate into written processes; gather information, develop content including graphics, proofread and edit technical documents *Develop process for archival and offsite storage of files including training materials and procedure development *Develop plan to create database connections for previously invisible information working with management and IT *Ability to understand, analyze, apply, & explain complex program statutes, regulations, policies, & procedures *Communicates effectively with both technical & non-technical users *Adjust workflow to complete critical tasks in a timely manner *Develop specific process for processing archival & offsite storage of files *Policy & procedure development *Maintain records of files & version controls *Write technically detailed, illustrated instructions for processes

ALASKA OFFICE SPECIALISTS

10 / 2008 - Present

Virtual Office Support Administrator

Alaska Office Specialists is a service-based business offering the services of technical writing, business writing, grant writing, document template creation, report writing, content writing (minimum standards apply to all writing). Hosting, setup and maintenance of WordPress based sites, social media management. visit www.alaskaos.com for more information.

SUE'S TINY COSTUMES 09 / 1995 - Present

Owner, Designer, Web Master

• Manage small business including product development, class development, web design & maintenance, marketing & budget • Write technically detailed, illustrated instructions for processes & doll patterns • Distance Education Teacher for pattern drafting classes • Research & write business, marketing, & merchandising plans • Project management including task management, goals, timelines and GANTT Charts • Set project goals, determine risks, prepare contingency plan, & time line for achievement • Collect & analyze data on customers to identify potential markets • Web site design & maintenance of hand coded websites • Install & maintain Wordpress sites • Proficient in white hat SEO techniques • Track keywords, visitors & other analytical data for each site • Troubleshoot hosting issues on hiatus

STATE OF ALASKA 05 / 2008 - 02 / 2014

Office Assistant II

Transitioned to the Senior Services Technician as my work as an Office Assistant II became more complex than the Office Assistant II position allows.

• Ability to understand, analyze, apply, & explain complex program statutes, regulations, policies, & procedures • Communicates effectively with both technical & non-technical users • Adjust workflow to complete critical tasks in a timely manner • Develop specific process for processing archival & offsite storage of files • Policy & procedure development • Maintain records of files & version controls • Write technically detailed, illustrated instructions for processes • Master Certified Office 2003, SharePoint (site owner) • Visio, Star UML, Project, • Organizing training sessions; materials gathering, staff/location coordination, equipment setup • Train additional staff on various processes & assign tasks overseeing accuracy

NINE STAR EDUCATION & EMPLOYMENT SERVICES

04/2006 - 04/2008

Career Development Mentor & Computer Instructor

• Organized training sessions; materials gathering, staff/location coordination, equipment setup • Developed class curriculum • Taught computer classes to adults • Taught goal setting workshops • Developed basic computer classes or work one on one with students to develop skills • Answered student questions about various software applications • Aided students in preparation for the Microsoft Office Specialist exams • Assessed clients for barriers & brainstorm ways to overcome them • Drafted & edited resumes, cover letters & other business correspondence • Conferred with clients to determine what program will be most helpful • Conducted job-matching to find good fit between clients & hiring companies • Directed clients to appropriate resources & assists clients in their use of outside assistance

EDUCATION

GNC WEB CREATIONS ONLINE SEARCH ENGINE OPTIMIZATION CLASS

2002 - 2020

none, SEO

Actively participate in online forum and group discussions on business and building websites.

CHARTER COLLEGE 2006 - 2009

Bachelors/Associates, Business Management Practice & Office Applications

Dean's List, Alpha Beta Kappa, Alpha Gamma Sigma

CHARTER COLLEGE 2006 - 2009

Bachelors Business Management & Information Technology

CERTIFICATIONS

MICROSOFT OFFICE MASTER Microsoft	03 / 2009
MSOS: MICROSOFT WORD 2003 Microsoft	03 / 2007
MSOS: MICROSOFT EXCEL 2003 Microsoft	09 / 2007
MSOS: MICROSOFT ACCESS 2003 Microsoft	11 / 2007
MSOS: MICROSOFT POWERPOINT 2003 Microsoft	10 / 2007
MSOE: MICROSOFT WORD 2003 EXPERT Microsoft	11/2007
MSOE: MICROSOFT EXCEL 2003 EXPERT Microsoft	03 / 2009

PUBLICATIONS

PATTERN MAKING FOR DOLLS

06 / 2001

 $\label{lem:compright} \textit{Copyright} & \cdot \textit{Authors: Sue Darby} & \cdot & \underline{\textit{http://www.suestinycostumes.com/Doll%20Clothing%20Patterns/doll-clothing-patterns/books/pattern-drafting-books/} \\ \\ \textit{Copyright} & \cdot & \underline{\textit{Nuthors: Sue Darby}} & \underline{\textit{http://www.suestinycostumes.com/Doll%20Clothing%20Patterns/doll-clothing-patterns/books/pattern-drafting-books/} \\ \\ \textit{Copyright} & \cdot & \underline{\textit{Nuthors: Sue Darby}} & \underline{\textit{http://www.suestinycostumes.com/Doll%20Clothing%20Patterns/doll-clothing-patterns/books/pattern-drafting-books/} \\ \\ \textit{Copyright} & \cdot & \underline{\textit{Nuthors: Sue Darby}} & \underline{\textit{http://www.suestinycostumes.com/Doll%20Clothing%20Patterns/doll-clothing-patterns/books/pattern-drafting-books/} \\ \\ \textit{Copyright} & \cdot & \underline{\textit{Nuthors: Sue Darby}} & \underline{\textit{http://www.suestinycostumes.com/Doll%20Clothing%20Patterns/doll-clothing-patterns/books/pattern-drafting-books/pattern-drafting-books/patterns/books/pattern-drafting-books/patterns/books/patterns$

Step-by-step guide to drafting for small dolls and fashion dolls. Fully illustrated and explained in detail how easy it is to measure and draft patterns "by the numbers" for dolls as small as 8" tall up to 46" tall. Originally self published in hard copy and now available as an e-book.

PATTERN DRAFTING FOR MINIATURES

06 / 2001

 $\label{lem:comprise} \textbf{Copyright} \quad \cdot \quad \textbf{Authors:} \quad \textbf{Sue} \quad \textbf{Darby} \quad \cdot \quad \underline{\text{http://www.suestinycostumes.com/Doll%20Clothing%20Patterns/doll-clothing-patterns/books/pattern-drafting-books/}$

Library of Congress http://lccn.loc.gov/2004540327

PATTERN CONSULTANT 06 / 2005

International Doll Magazine · Authors: Sue Darby

Multiple articles in bi-monthly doll magazine including Little Bo Peep, Wedding Gown and "Dirty Dancing" inspired dresses for several dolls

PUBLISHED PATTERNS 06 / 2004

Dolls In MIniature · Authors: Sue Darby

Pattern for miniature smocked baby dress for 1/12 scale doll.